A Guide to the Richmond (Va.) Civil War Centennial Committee records, circa 1956-1965
Library of Virginia
- Committee Projects [S-T], 1956-1965. (Barcodenumber 1051314)
  - Soldier and Sailors Monument. (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Sons-Union Vets. (Box 23, Folder 6)
    Papers relating to the Sons of Union Veterans of the Civil War.
  - Southern Historical Society Papers. (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Speech Material. (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - State Protest. (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - State Exhibits. (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - State Ceremonies, 1961 April 23. (Box 23, Folder 11)
    Ceremonies organized by the Virginia Civil War Centennial Commission. The opening of the Civil War Centennial occurred on April 23, 1961.
  - Street Signs. (Box 23, Folder 12)
  - Stuart Ride Reenactment, 1956 October 6. (Box 23, Folder 13)
    Stuart's ride around McClellan, reenacted by the Richmond Civil War Round Table.
  - Suggested Projects. (Box 23, Folder 14)
  - Survey and Register of Civil War Material. (Box 23, Folder 15)
    Register of Civil War items held in private collections.
  - Tour Brochures. (Box 23, Folder 16)
  - Trailer Information Booths. (Box 23, Folder 17)
    Proposal for road-side information booths housed in trailers.
  - Travel Program. (Box 23, Folder 18)
- Committee Projects [U-WRVA], 1959-1965. (Barcodenumber 1051319)
  - US "Surrender Richmond" Flag. (Box 24, Folder 1)
    Relates to the flag flown by the Federal forces after they overtook Richmond.
  - Vignettes, Spring 1965. (Box 24, Folder 2)
    "Vignettes of the Civil War," a walking tour of four downtown Richmond Civil War shrines offered by the Civil War Centennial Committee.
  - Vignettes, Fall 1964. (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Vignettes, Spring 1964. (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Vignettes, 1963 Fall. (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Vignettes, Spring 1963. (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Vignettes, Fall 1962. (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Vignettes, Spring 1962. (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - Virginia Military Institute. (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - WRVA Civil War Movie Script. (Box 24, Folder 10)
    Script of film produced by WRVA television.
- Committee Projects [Week-West]; Personal Correspondence of the Chair, 1959-1965; 1959 December-1960 August. (Barcodenumber 1051320)
  Committee projects arranged alphabetically; Personal correspondence arranged chronologically.
  - Weekend Centennial Ball, 1961 May 27. (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Weitzel Manuscript Project: Weitzel Biographical Material. (Box 25, Folder 2)
    General Godfrey Weitzel.
  - Weitzel Manuscript Project: Miscellaneous Biographical Material. (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Weitzel Manuscript Project: Mr. Waitt's Working Papers. (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Weitzel Manuscript Project: Mr. Waitt's Working Papers. (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - West Virginia Centennial Band. (Box 25, Folder 5)
    West Virginia's all-state band, which made an appearance in Richmond as part of the Centennial celebration.
  - Personal Correspondence of the Chairman, 1959 March-December. (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Personal Correspondence of the Chairman, 1960 Jan-June. (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - Personal Correspondence of the Chairman, 1960 July-August. (Box 25, Folder 8)
- Personal Correspondence of the Chair, 1960 September-1962 April. (Barcodenumber 1051321)
  Arranged chronologically.
  - Personal Correspondence of the Chairman, 1960 September-October. (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Personal Correspondence of the Chairman, 1960 November-1961 January. (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Personal Correspondence of the Chairman, 1961 Feb-May. (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Personal Correspondence of the Chairman, 1961 June-Oct. (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Personal Correspondence of the Chairman, 1961 Nov-1962 Jan. (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Personal Correspondence of the Chairman, 1962 Feb-Apr. (Box 26, Folder 6)
- Personal Correspondence of the Chair, 1962 May-1965 May. (Barcodenumber 1051316)
  - Personal Correspondence of the Chairman, 1962 May-1963 May. (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Personal Correspondence of the Chairman, 1963 June-Dec. (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Personal Correspondence of the Chairman, 1964 Jan-Aug. (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Personal Correspondence of the Chairman, 1964 Sept-Nov. (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Personal Correspondence of the Chairman, 1964 Dec-1965 Jan. (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Personal Correspondence of the Chairman, 1965 Feb-April. (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Personal Correspondence of the Chairman, 1965 May. (Box 27, Folder 7)
- Personal Correspondence of the Chair, 1958-1960 June, 1965 June-1966 Jan. (Barcodenumber 1051317)
  - Personal Correspondence of the Chairman, 1965 June. (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Personal Correspondence of the Chairman, 1965 July-1966 Jan. (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Personal Correspondence of the Chairman [US and VA] Civil War Centennial Commission, 1958. (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Personal Correspondence of the Chairman [US and VA] Civil War Centennial Commission, 1959 Jan-June. (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - Personal Correspondence of the Chairman [US and VA] Civil War Centennial Commission, 1959 July-Oct. (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - Personal Correspondence of the Chairman [US and VA] Civil War Centennial Commission, 1959 Nov-1960 June. (Box 28, Folder 6)
- Personal correspondence of the chairman, Civil War Centennial Commission, 1960 July-1965 June. (Barcodenumber 1051318)
  - Personal Correspondence of the Chairman [US and VA] Civil War Centennial Commission, 1960 July-1961 Feb. (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Personal Correspondence of the Chairman [US and VA] Civil War Centennial Commission, 1961 Mar-Oct. (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Personal Correspondence of the Chairman [US and VA] Civil War Centennial Commission, 1961 Nov-1962 Mar. (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Personal Correspondence of the Chairman [US and VA] Civil War Centennial Commission, 1962 Apr-1963 May. (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Personal Correspondence of the Chairman [US and VA] Civil War Centennial Commission, 1963 June-1965 June. (Box 29, Folder 5)
- Civil War Centennial: Research Files and Correspondence. (Barcodenumber 1031088, Box 30)
  Research files from projects undertaken by the Richmond Civil War Centennial Committee, as well as correspondence from the committee.
- Civil War Centennial: Photographs, maps and publications1959-1965. (Barcodenumber 1031085, Box 31)
  Box contains primarily photographs, many of which are copies from the Library of Congress, the National Archives, or ones created by the Richmond Civil War Centennial Committee, as well as a few maps (several copies of one produced for the Richmond Civil War Centennial Committee) and photo negatives. Most of the photographs fall within two categories: 1. Copies of Civil War-era photographs. 2. Photographs taken at Civil War Centennial events. Box also contains several issues of Civil War Times Illustrated and a file of publications produced by the Richmond Civil War Centennial Committee.
- Civil War Centennial: Transcripts of Richmond City Council Minutes (1861-1864), 1959-1965. (Barcodenumber 1031085, Box 32)
  Box contains annotated copies of Richmond City Council minutes from the years during the Civil War, later published by the Richmond Civil War Centennial Committee.
- Civil War Centennial: Maps, Photostats, 1959-1965. (Barcodenumber 1031064, Box 33)
  Box contains rolled-up copies of maps of the Richmond area, relating to the Civil War. Most are photostats of maps from the National Archives.